Curriculum Vitae - Ian Nisbet

Name: Ian Nisbet Address: Ilford, Essex, UK
Date of birth: 1974 E-mail: ian@nisbet.com

Nationality: English Github and Twitter: nisbeti

Career Overview

lan is a confident engineer and self-motivated masters graduate with proven managerial skills and having good communication skills built through teamwork and managerial experience. Ian has experience in a variety of disciplines while working as an IT Consultant for corporate, international and individual clientele.

Selections from Employment History

Glutenite - London

2013 – present: Director and developer

Responsibilities: Consulting, programming, architecture, deployment, database, training, writing.

Client web development including Kobi Nazrul School website, iPad web-app for Managed property inventory, multi-lingual searchable app for library of over 3 million pages, CMS for community site,

Money Management site, e-commerce sites...

London College of Business – Barking, Essex

2010 – present: Bachelors Director, then Project Manager for Online MBA, and Principal

Responsibilities: Programming, architecture, deployment, database, managing small IT and development team.

Coordinating temporary and permanent staff, designing syllabus, teaching, negotiating contracts, quality assurance of university and external body regulations, pastoral care of students, dispute

resolution, presenting graduation ceremonies, marketing, business development.

Development of company websites, Moodle plugins, API integrations, Paypal payments, CRM

system, two versions of college MIS.

Jo Richardson Community School - Dagenham, Essex

2007 – 2009: Teacher of Mathematics

Responsibilities: Teaching KS3 and KS4. Planning lessons, designing module SoW and creating resources. Form

tutor. Development and use of VLE system in school. Designing department assessment policy.

E-maginedotnet – based in Cairo, Egypt

2001 – 2002: Senior Partner in design and development Agency

Responsibilities: Development and maintenance of client websites using Perl, PHP and ASP. Managing team of 5

designers and programmers. Mentoring and training.

Henderson Global Investors - based in Central London

2001: Webmaster (Contract)

Responsibilities: Daily running of investment bank's internet website. Design and implementation of new pages. Web-

server management. Risk Assessment. Other internal development using ASP, XML and Perl.

Mawhoob.com - based in Cairo, Egypt

2001: IT Manager

Responsibilities: Daily management of IT department comprising 10 programming and 4 administration staff, including

interviewing, hiring and firing. Design and development of *mawhoob* database, website and IT infrastructure. IT services supplier sourcing. Mentoring, training and technical problem-shooting. Perl

and ASP programming.

Online Publishing Education - LearnOnline development - based in Central London

1999 – 2001: Head of Technology, Lead Programmer

Responsibilities: Lead developer for Internet Application Service Provider. Architecture, design, programming and

deployment of product. Managing support, testers and external graphic designers. Liaising with

CMO, CTO and CEO.

Company produced a commercial distance-learning internet application, and client web-site applications. Perl, ASP, JS and Active X core design accessing SQL Server database. Integrated with third-party APIs. Client-facing installation, support and exhibition marketing.

Client websites: TUC, Lewisham College, Northumberland College

Phillips Global Network project - based in Phillips Headquarters, Eindhoven, Netherlands

1998 - 1999: Client-Server Database and Intranet Developer (Contract)

Responsibilities: Corporate (Phillips) world-wide Intranet and ASP database solution design and implementation for

use in over 35 countries. Visual Interdev ASP page design and debugging, Systems analysis, MS Access Database design and creation, MS SQL Server Database Design and Creation, Access and SQL Server Data Access Techniques, MS IIS Installation, configuration and maintenance, MS NT4 Server installation, configuration, maintenance and support, Active X Objects, VBScript, VBA, Data

Migration Techniques.

Personal Projects

I have worked on a number of websites as an IT consultant responsible for design, content advise, contractual management, business planning, recruiting and training. I have programmed many personal and charitable web applications since 1999. Projects are typically PHP/MySql based, but have used a wide range of technologies, front and back-end. I have had technical responsibility for two Arena sized conferences, each with over 7,000 delegates.

Professional Training

Technical: VueJS, Moodle Admin, Interwoven TeamSite, Linux, Asymetrix IconAuthor (Amethyst), SuiteSpot

(Netscape), Microsoft Network Installation and Configuration

Business: Teamwork, Benchmarking to be the Best, Westinghouse Business Process Re-Engineering,

PRINCE Project Methodology (Royal Mail), Various teaching CPD programmes.

Qualifications

2010 – 2014: University of Wales. MBA Business Analysis

1992 - 1996: University of Westminster. B.Eng. Computer and Control Engineering

Course units including Computer Eng., Software Eng., Microprocessors, Advanced

Digital Systems Design, Telecommunications, Management, C, C++, Control, Signal Processing,

Assembly language programming.

Result: 2.2 B.Eng. with Honours

Techniques Overview

Front End JS programming API Consumption Internet Networking
Internet App Programming Mathematical Computation Client-Server
Backend API programming Database Administration Real time software

Database Schema Design Plugin Design

Technical Skills Overview

Backend dev	PHP, Perl, ASP, C, SQL OsX, Windows, Ubuntu, Redhat Apache, Nginx, IIS MySQL, Sqlite, MS SQL Server AWS EC2 Slim, Laravel, Laravel Spark, Moodle, Wordpress, Twig PHPUnit, Codeception, Selenium Node, NPM, Yarn
Frontend dev	JS, JQuery, Vue, HTML, Json, CSS, Sass, Gulp, Foundation, Responsive
API	AWS S3, Slack, Stripe, Paypal, Mailgun, Pusher, Imgix, G Suite, TextLocal, Github
Other Internet	DNS, Travis, Git, Adwords
Hardware	Electronics / laptop servicing / repair; Electronics design and software engineering; PCB.
Other	Built 8 Track recording studio, VBA, Motorola MC68HC11 / 68000 Assembly Code